A STORY BASED ON REAL EVENTS
THE SILENT HOUSE
He hasn't arrived yet.
It's so neglected here.
Better to start with the grass at the back
and work towards the front.
- What are you doing?
- Just looking.
Wilson, how are you?
- Sorry for the delay.
- It's okay. How are you?
Fine. It's been so long.
As I said, I want to sell the house-
- But first I have to tidy it all up. Have you seen it?
- Yes.
I told my daughter to get up early, to take advantage of the day.
- I brought some water and blankets.
- Laura!
- How are things in the village?
- Nothing changes.
One realizes time passes when we see our kids.
You're planning on selling?
Yes. I live in the city now-
- And my brother and I want to sell off all our properties around here.
We won't be seeing you around anymore?
I'll always come back. Memories, you know what I mean.
- Have you been waiting long?
- No, we just arrived.
Ok. Let's go inside.
Here's another lamp, Laura.
Wilson, come with me.
It's worse than I thought.
It's even worse upstairs.
Loose tiles everywhere. It's dangerous. Don't go up.
Come through here.
Come on, Wilson.
There are some candles here.
- Here are some sofas. Will you be ok?
- Perfectly fine.
We can manage everywhere. Don't worry.
How much time will you need?
I was thinking two or three days. If the weather's good.
We thought we'd start from the back,
go around, and finish up in front.
- Do you agree?
- Of course. You're the expert.
- Ok, that's our plan.
- By the way ...
Come have a look.
This door ...
will be very useful for access to the front.
Okay.
Fine.
Here are the keys. I'll be back with food later on.
- No, don't worry.
- It doesn't bother me.
I'll show you out.
- Anyone interested?
- It's a matter of weeks.
Negotiations have already been going on for a while.
Laura, I'll leave you this.
Dad!
- Did you hear that?
- What!
That noise.
- What noise?
- There's somebody outside.
There's no one, Laura. Go back to sleep.
Dad, wake up!
Did you not hear that?
- What!
- Those noises again.
Upstairs, Dad, please.
Ok. Here's what we'll do.
I'll go up and look.
But when I come down,
I want you to be asleep. Ok?
Dad!
What happened to you?
Wake up, Dad.
Wake up.
What happened?
Calm down.
What did they do? What happened?
What happened?
Calm down.
What happened.
Tell me what's going on.
- We were attacked.
- Who?
I don't know.
- No, don't go!
- Stop it.
I'll have a look.
- Where's your father? Where is he?
- I don't know.
- Let's find him.
- I don't want to go.
I don't want to go.
No, don't go.
- Wait here, I'll have a look.
- Please... don't go.
- Come on!
- I don't want to go.
It's more dangerous here. There's nobody.
There's nobody! Come on.
Come on.
Did you move the furniture?
- Nestor. Nestor!
- stay there!
Wilson!
Put that down.
Laura ...
Where's your father?
I don't know.
Where did they attack you?
Upstairs.
You went upstairs...
Wilson! Wilson!
Keep calm.
Here.
Stay there.
I told you not to go upstairs.
Why did you go up?
Dad!
He isn't here.
He isn't here, Laura.
No one's been upstairs in a while.
Let's go, Laura. He isn't here.
Nestor?
Nestor!
What did they do to you?
Are you okay?
What happened?
Who attacked you? Look at me.
Nestor...
What's going on in this house?
Why, Laura?
Why?
I saw the pictures.
- Which pictures?
- The photographs.
- What are you talking about?
- The photographs in your room!
Photographs!
What are you saying, Laura?
Do you miss her?
- Who?
- Her.
- Our daughter. Do you miss her?
- Tell her. She's there.
- I miss you.
You're lying!
Do you love me?
Do you?
Why didn't you come?
I've been waiting for you.
I'm here with you.
I'm here.
Help me.
Shut up!
Laura...
I called your father because I wanted to see you. That's why I called him.
- I needed to see you.
- Shut up!
- Don't you remember?
Do you remember ... we agreed to talk it over.
You knew we could not keep her.
What have you done to your father? Did you kill him, Laura?
- I told you to shut up!
- He knew this was for the best ...
Listen...
Shut up!
You lied to me!
He lied to me like you did...
You killed my baby!
You're going to die like my dad!
Smile...
Smile!
Six days later, the mutilated bodies were found
next to disturbing Polaroid photos.
Despite the amount of evidence, the police investigation was inconclusive.
The case was closed eight months later.
Laura was never found.
Sofi!
How lovely!
- Were you playing?
- Yes.
Shall we visit grandma?
It's been a long time since we saw her.
We're going to ride horses
- And eat caramel.
Let's go this way.
And we're going to swim.
Do you feel like swimming?
Because Grandma has a canoe.
It's like a little boat.
You know what a canoe is? No?
It's a really tiny boat.
with room for...
all three of us,
you, grandmother and I.
And the doll can go too.
You know Grandma's looking
forward to meeting you?
But she lives far away...
We have to walk
and walk and walk...
And there ...
We can see...
a lot of sun.
in the countryside.
What do you say?
No.
Or don't you feel like walking?
Sofi, I love you so much.
You know there's
a little house in a tree.
When I was a little girl,
I used to play there everyday.
You can use it too.
- It's near the lake.
- You know that lake?